|                           Method                          |         Return Value         |                                                                                                       Description                                                                                                        |
|-----------------------------------------------------------|------------------------------|--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| on_new(view)                                              | None                         | Called when a new buffer is created.                                                                                                                                                                                     |
| on_new_async(view)                                        | None                         | Called when a new buffer is created. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                                      |
| on_clone(view)                                            | None                         | Called when a view is cloned from an existing one.                                                                                                                                                                       |
| on_clone_async(view)                                      | None                         | Called when a view is cloned from an existing one. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                        |
| on_load(view)                                             | None                         | Called when the file is finished loading.                                                                                                                                                                                |
| on_load_async(view)                                       | None                         | Called when the file is finished loading. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                                 |
| on_pre_close(view)                                        | None                         | Called when a view is about to be closed. The view will still be in the window at this point.                                                                                                                            |
| on_close(view)                                            | None                         | Called when a view is closed (note, there may still be other views into the same buffer).                                                                                                                                |
| on_pre_save(view)                                         | None                         | Called just before a view is saved.                                                                                                                                                                                      |
| on_pre_save_async(view)                                   | None                         | Called just before a view is saved. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                                       |
| on_post_save(view)                                        | None                         | Called after a view has been saved.                                                                                                                                                                                      |
| on_post_save_async(view)                                  | None                         | Called after a view has been saved. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                                       |
| on_modified(view)                                         | None                         | Called after changes have been made to a view.                                                                                                                                                                           |
| on_modified_async(view)                                   | None                         | Called after changes have been made to a view. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                            |
| on_selection_modified(view)                               | None                         | Called after the selection has been modified in a view.                                                                                                                                                                  |
| on_selection_modified_async(view)                         | None                         | Called after the selection has been modified in a view. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                   |
| on_activated(view)                                        | None                         | Called when a view gains input focus.                                                                                                                                                                                    |
| on_activated_async(view)                                  | None                         | Called when a view gains input focus. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                                     |
| on_deactivated(view)                                      | None                         | Called when a view loses input focus.                                                                                                                                                                                    |
| on_deactivated_async(view)                                | None                         | Called when a view loses input focus. Runs in a separate thread, and does not block the application.                                                                                                                     |
| on_text_command(view, command_name, args)                 | (new_command_name, new_args) | Called when a text command is issued. The listener may return a (command, arguments) tuple to rewrite the command, or None to run the command unmodified.                                                                |
| on_window_command(window, command_name, args)             | (new_command_name, new_args) | Called when a window command is issued. The listener may return a (command, arguments) tuple to rewrite the command, or None to run the command unmodified.                                                              |
| post_text_command(view, command_name, args)               | None                         | Called after a text command has been executed.                                                                                                                                                                           |
| post_window_command(window, command_name, args)           | None                         | Called after a window command has been executed.                                                                                                                                                                         |
| on_query_context(view, key, operator, operand, match_all) | bool or None                 | Called when determining to trigger a key binding with the given context key. If the plugin knows how to respond to the context, it should return either True of False. If the context is unknown, it should return None. |
|                                                           |                              |                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |
|                                                           |                              | operator is one of:                                                                                                                                                                                                      |
|                                                           |                              |                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |
|                                                           |                              | sublime.OP_EQUAL. Is the value of the context equal to the operand?                                                                                                                                                      |
|                                                           |                              | sublime.OP_NOT_EQUAL. Is the value of the context not equal to the operand?                                                                                                                                              |
|                                                           |                              | sublime.OP_REGEX_MATCH. Does the value of the context match the regex given in operand?                                                                                                                                  |
|                                                           |                              | sublime.OP_NOT_REGEX_MATCH. Does the value of the context not match the regex given in operand?                                                                                                                          |
|                                                           |                              | sublime.OP_REGEX_CONTAINS. Does the value of the context contain a substring matching the regex given in operand?                                                                                                        |
|                                                           |                              | sublime.OP_NOT_REGEX_CONTAINS. Does the value of the context not contain a substring matching the regex given in operand?                                                                                                |
|                                                           |                              |                                                                                                                                                                                                                          |
|                                                           |                              | match_all should be used if the context relates to the selections: does every selection have to match (match_all = True), or is at least one matching enough (match_all = Fals)?                                         |
