|                                     Method                                    |  Return Value  |                                                                                                                                  Description                                                                                                                                  |
|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------|----------------|-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------|
| id()                                                                          | int            | Returns a number that uniquely identifies this window.                                                                                                                                                                                                                        |
| new_file()                                                                    | View           | Creates a new file. The returned view will be empty, and its is_loaded method will return True.                                                                                                                                                                               |
| open_file(file_name, <flags>)                                                 | View           | Opens the named file, and returns the corresponding view. If the file is already opened, it will be brought to the front. Note that as file loading is asynchronous, operations on the returned view won't be possible until its is_loading() method returns False.           |
|                                                                               |                | The optional flags parameter is a bitwise combination of:                                                                                                                                                                                                                     |
|                                                                               |                | sublime.ENCODED_POSITION. Indicates the file_name should be searched for a :row or :row:col suffix                                                                                                                                                                            |
|                                                                               |                | sublime.TRANSIENT. Open the file as a preview only: it won't have a tab assigned it until modified                                                                                                                                                                            |
| find_open_file(file_name)                                                     | View           | Finds the named file in the list of open files, and returns the corresponding View, or None if no such file is open.                                                                                                                                                          |
| active_view()                                                                 | View           | Returns the currently edited view.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |
| active_view_in_group(group)                                                   | View           | Returns the currently edited view in the given group.                                                                                                                                                                                                                         |
| views()                                                                       | [View]         | Returns all open views in the window.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                         |
| views_in_group(group)                                                         | [View]         | Returns all open views in the given group.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    |
| num_groups()                                                                  | int            | Returns the number of view groups in the window.                                                                                                                                                                                                                              |
| active_group()                                                                | int            | Returns the index of the currently selected group.                                                                                                                                                                                                                            |
| focus_group(group)                                                            | None           | Makes the given group active.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |
| focus_view(view)                                                              | None           | Switches to the given view.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |
| get_view_index(view)                                                          | (group, index) | Returns the group, and index within the group of the view. Returns -1 if not found.                                                                                                                                                                                           |
| set_view_index(view, group, index)                                            | None           | Moves the view to the given group and index.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                  |
| folders()                                                                     | [String]       | Returns a list of the currently open folders.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 |
| project_file_name()                                                           | String         | Returns name of the currently opened project file, if any.                                                                                                                                                                                                                    |
| project_data()                                                                | Dictionary     | Returns the project data associated with the current window. The data is in the same format as the contents of a .sublime-project file.                                                                                                                                       |
| set_project_data(data)                                                        | None           | Updates the project data associated with the current window. If the window is associated with a .sublime-project file, the project file will be updated on disk, otherwise the window will store the data internally.                                                         |
| run_command(string, <args>)                                                   | None           | Runs the named Command with the (optional) given arguments. Window.run_command is able to run both any sort of command, dispatching the command via input focus.                                                                                                              |
| show_quick_panel(items, on_done, <flags>, <selected_index>, <on_highlighted>) | None           | Shows a quick panel, to select an item in a list. on_done will be called once, with the index of the selected item. If the quick panel was cancelled, on_done will be called with an argument of -1.   [[obj\show_quick_panel.py]]                                            |
|                                                                               |                | Items may be an array of strings, or an array of string arrays. In the latter case, each entry in the quick panel will show multiple rows.                                                                                                                                    |
|                                                                               |                | Flags currently only has one option, sublime.MONOSPACE_FONT                                                                                                                                                                                                                   |
|                                                                               |                | on_highlighted, if given, will be called every time the highlighted item in the quick panel is changed.                                                                                                                                                                       |
| show_input_panel(caption, initial_text, on_done, on_change, on_cancel)        | View           | Shows the input panel, to collect a line of input from the user. on_done and on_change, if not None, should both be functions that expect a single string argument. on_cancel should be a function that expects no arguments. The view used for the input widget is returned. |
| create_output_panel(name)                                                     | View           | Returns the view associated with the named output panel, created it if required. The output panel can be shown by running the show_panel window command, with the panel argument set to the name with an "output." prefix.                                                    |
| lookup_symbol_in_index(symbol)                                                | [Location]     | Returns all locations where the symbol is defined across files in the current project.                                                                                                                                                                                        |
| lookup_symbol_in_open_files(symbol)                                           | [Location]     | Returns all locations where the symbol is defined across open files.                                                                                                                                                                                                          |
