Open current file with external programs
Can use Absolute OR Relative path to external executables.
Can use the path element in .sublime-build files to override the Relative PATH
Many packages include their own build systems.
Running Build Systems: Tools | Build (F7)

Config by .sublime-build (JSON format), example:
    {
        "cmd": ["python.exe", "-u", "$file"],                   //Actual command line to be executed i.e:  python -u /path/to/current/file.ext
        "file_regex": "^[ ]*File \"(...*?)\", line ([0-9]*)",   //Perl-style Regex to capture error info from external program’s output
        "selector": "source.python"  //If enable Tools | Build System | Automatic → ST auto find proper build system for active file
        "path": "C:\program files\Python"                   //Path to external prog if its short name (python.exe) is not register in the OS
    }

"cmd": ["path-to-external-prog", "output option", "argument"]
    Output Option can be:
        "-l"  =  lint (output error message only)
        "-u"  =  Output final result
    Argument is the command-line parameter passed to external prog. Variables can be:
        | $file_path         | The directory of the current file, e.g., C:\Files.              |
        | $file              | The full path to the current file, e.g., C:\Files\Chapter1.txt. |
        | $file_name         | The name portion of the current file, e.g., Chapter1.txt.       |
        | $file_extension    | The extension portion of the current file, e.g., txt.           |
        | $file_base_name    | The name-only portion of the current file, e.g., Document.      |
        | $packages          | The full path to the Packages folder.                           |
        | $project           | The full path to the current project file.                      |
        | $project_path      | The directory of the current project file.                      |
        | $project_name      | The name portion of the current project file.                   |
        | $project_extension | The extension portion of the current project file.              |
        | $project_base_name | The name-only portion of the current project file.              |
        (*) Can use Placeholders (similar to snippets), i.e:
            ${project_name:Default}  =  Emit the name of the current project if there is one, otherwise Default.
            ${file/\.php/\.txt/}  =  Emit the full path of the current file, replacing .php with .txt.

Other optional options:
    line_regex  =  If file_regex doesn’t match on the current line, but line_regex exists, and it does match on the current line, then walk backwards through the buffer until a line matching file regex is found, and use these two matches to determine the file and line to go to.
    working_dir  =  Directory to change the current directory to before running cmd. The original current directory is restored afterwards.
    encoding  =  Output encoding of cmd. Must be a valid Python encoding. Defaults to UTF-8.
    target  =  Sublime Text command to run. Defaults to exec (Packages/Default/exec.py). This command receives the configuration data specified in the .build-system file. Used to override the default build system command. Note that if you choose to override the default command for build systems, you can add arbitrary variables in the .sublime-build file.
    env  =  Dictionary of environment variables to be merged with the current process’ before passing them to cmd. Use this element, for example, to add or modify environment variables without modifying your system’s settings.
    shell  =  If true, cmd will be run through the shell (cmd.exe, bash...).
    path  =  This string will replace the current process’ PATH before calling cmd. The old PATH value will be restored after that. Use this option to add directories to PATH without having to modify your system’s settings.
    variants  =  A list of dictionaries of options to override the main build system’s options. Variant ``name``s will appear in the Command Palette for easy access if the build system’s selector matches for the active file.
    name  =  Only valid inside a variant (see variants). Identifies variant build systems. If name is Run, the variant will show up under the Tools | Build System menu and be bound to Ctrl + Shift + B.
    syntax  =  When provided, the build system output will be formatted with the provided syntax definition.
    file_regex  =  Perl-style Regex to capture error info from external program’s output. It Capture 4 info: filename, line number, column number, error message. filename field and the line number field are required.

Can use variables:
